(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-28T22:23:38.060734",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.6-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
百鬼あやめ 7周年記念ライブ「天女繚華」
[Nakiri Ayame 7th Anniversary Live: Tennyo Ryōka]
ゆらゆらり
Swaying gently,
はらはらり
fluttering down,
色とりどり 乱れ咲き
blooming in profusion with vivid colors,
花の街 思い出す
I recall the city of flowers
この空から
from high up in this sky.
百花繚乱
[Song: Hyakka Ryōran]
いろんな出来事から
From various events and experiences,
やってきたこの場所は
this place I have arrived at...
遥か遠くにあった
was once so far away—
煌びやかな舞台
a dazzling, splendid stage.
ハッとするほど
So striking that it takes my breath away,
鮮やかな世界があるんだと知った
I learned that such a vivid world exists.
あなたの無理難題に
To your impossible demands,
応えてゆくその度に
every time I respond and meet them,
あっと言わせるような
I reach an astonishing,
奇想天外な答え合わせで
unpredictable resolution,
辿り着いたその先に
and beyond the place I finally reached,
新しい景色が待っているんだ
a brand-new scenery is waiting.
摩訶不思議なミスタリィ
A wondrous, mysterious mystery,
次から次に起こるたび
every time it happens one after another,
巧妙なからくりも 暴いてみせましょう
I shall expose even the most clever tricks.
どんな難題でも
No matter how difficult the challenge,
種や仕掛けはあるんだ
there is always a trick or mechanism behind it.
副作用は気にしない
I won't worry about side effects,
必ずや導き出すから
for I will surely find the answer.
あぁ この場所で触れた
Ah, touched in this place,
人の哀しみや喜びがある
there lies people's sorrow and joy.
そのひとつひとつが
Every single one of them
心を震わせる
makes my heart tremble.
ハッとしちゃうほど
So much that it startles me,
鮮やかな世界が ここにあるんだ
a vivid world is right here.
あなたの無理難題に 応えていく毎日に
In these days spent answering your impossible demands,
アッと言わせるような
like an astounding,
奇想天外な答え合わせで
fantastic alignment of answers,
辿り着いたその先に
beyond where we've reached,
新しい私が待っているんだ
a new me is waiting.
あの頃は 想像もしない
Back then, a future I couldn't even imagine
未来が咲き始めている
is starting to bloom.
こんな日々も悪くはないかな
Days like these aren't so bad, I guess.
ゆらゆらり ひらひらり
Swaying gently, fluttering lightly,
離れ離れては 寄り添って
drifting apart and coming close again,
そよぐ風に身を任せ
leaving myself to the gentle breeze,
幽夜に舞う
dancing in the tranquil night.
はーい！ということで
All right! So then,
今日は皆さん来てくれてありがとー！
thank you so much for coming today, everyone!
みんな見えてる？見えてますかー？
Can everyone see me? Can you see me?
ということで見て！今日はこの新衣装なんですよ！
Look at this! I'm wearing my new outfit today!
みんな気づいたよね？気づいたよね？さすがに！
You all noticed, right? You noticed, right? Of course you did!
はい！ということで見てください！このきらびやかな和風の新衣装です！
Yes! So take a look! This is my gorgeous, Japanese-style new outfit!
やったー！
Yay!
ということでですね、こちらは今回「天女衣装」となっております！
So, this outfit is designed as a celestial maiden outfit!
傘も合わせて見てください！傘！ちょっと見えるかな？
Take a look at the umbrella too! Can you see it?
これ見て！余のね、ちょっと衣装と同じ柄で今回新しく作っていただきました！
Look at this! It was custom-made with the exact same pattern as my outfit!
イェーイ！ありがとうございます！
Yay! Thank you so much!
はい、ということでこの傘以外にもですね、この後新しいアイテムもちょっと出てくるのでそちらも要チェックです！
Yes! Besides this umbrella, some other new items will appear later, so stay tuned for those too!
というわけで、1曲目は『百花繚乱』を歌って踊らせていただきました！
And so, for my first song, I sang and danced to "Hyakka Ryouran"!
あのね、ちょっと花の蕾を使ってちょっと新衣装にチェンジさせていただいたんですけど、どうでしたー？
You know, I used a flower bud to transform into this new outfit—how was it?
どうだった？
How was it?
お〜ありがとうございます！可愛いですよね！
Oh~ thank you so much! It's super cute, right?
はい、ということで今回のライブタイトルが『天女繚華』ということで
Yes! And so, the title of this live concert is "Tennyo Ryouraka"...
ちょっとこの新衣装チェンジとか、これからのゲストの登場とかで、お花を多く使っているので
...and because we're using lots of flowers for the outfit change and guest appearances...
花が咲き乱れるという意味を込めて、今回この『天女繚華』というライブ名にさせていただきました！
...we named it "Tennyo Ryouraka" with the meaning of flowers blooming in profusion!
見て、ちょっとね、後ろにもちらっとお花が見えたり
Look, you can see glimpses of flowers behind me...
余の衣装にもね、ちょっとお花があったりなんだりしているんですけれども
...and my outfit has flower details on it too!
はい！ということで、この衣装に合わせて今回もステージを新しく作っていただきました！
Yes! So to go with this outfit, they built a brand new stage for me this time as well!
やったー！
Yay!
え、めっちゃ綺麗じゃない？見て！この桜と
Woah, isn't it so pretty? Look! The cherry blossoms and...
このでっかい月！このでっかい月とね、両端に...こっちにもありますけど、桜！
...this huge moon! This huge moon and the cherry blossoms on both sides—there's more over here too!
いや、めちゃめちゃ綺麗でしょー！すごいでしょ、これ！
Seriously, isn't it insanely beautiful?! Isn't this amazing?!
もうめっちゃ考えました！
I put so much thought into it!
めちゃくちゃね、ちょっと運営さんたちと一緒にお話し合いをしたりとかして実現していただきました！本当ありがとうございます！
I had so many discussions with the staff to bring this to life! Thank you all so much!
ということで、この床にもね...分かります？気づきました？
And so, on the floor too... do you see it? Did you notice?
ちょっとね、お花もこの散りばめられていたり
There are flowers scattered all over...
余の足元にはね、この...梅なのかな？このお花をこうね、ライトみたいな感じで照らしていただいたり
...and under my feet, these plum blossoms, maybe? They made them shine like lights!
細かくめっちゃ作ってもらってます！ありがとうございます！
They made everything in such incredible detail! Thank you so much!
なのでそれも含めてちょっとめちゃめちゃ見ていただきたいなと思っております！
So I really hope you all take a close look at all these details!
まぁこのね、気になりますよね？この衣装！ちょっとみんなで近くで見てもらおうかな？
Well, you're curious about this outfit, right? Should I let everyone take a closer look?
あ、ちょっと上から...いいですか、カメラさん？あ、ありがとうございます！
Ah, from above... is that okay, camera person? Ah, thank you so much!
あ、このね、気づきました？髪型からもうちょっといつもと違うんですよ！
Ah, did you notice? Even my hairstyle is a bit different from usual!
ちょっとお団子...いつもの3D衣装の雰囲気も残しつつ、新しい髪型にさせていただきました！
With these buns... while keeping the feel of my usual 3D outfit, I got a new hairstyle!
そしてそして？ちょっといいですか？あ！あら！あら可愛いですよね！
And also? Can I show a bit? Ah! My! Isn't it so cute?!
このお花
These flowers...
そう、ステージの各所にも入っているこのね、梅っぽい花っぽい感じも
Incorporating this plum-like, flower-like feel,
入れていただきつつ、この見て！
into various parts of the stage as well—look at this!
見てください！
Please take a look!
あ、この振袖にもちゃんと付いてます、このお花。
Ah, these flowers are properly included on these long sleeves too.
綺麗でしょ〜。見て、綺麗でしょ〜。
Pretty, right? Look, isn't it pretty?
超可愛いでしょ〜。良いでしょ〜。
Super cute, right? Isn't it great?
はい、ということでね、足元にもちょっと注目していただきたいんですけど...
Alright, so I'd like you to pay attention to my feet as well...
見て！草履も新しくなりました〜！
Look! The zori sandals are brand new too!
可愛いよね！草履ね、ちょっと袖の色と合わせて...
Cute, right? The sandals match the color of the sleeves...
こっちはね、白で。こっちはちょっと茶色っぽい感じになってます。
This side is white, while this side has a brownish feel.
そしてね、この衣装のすごいところね、どんだけ踊ってもですよ、足元見てください！
And the amazing thing about this outfit is—no matter how much I dance, look at my feet!
めっちゃ伸びるんです、これ！すごいでしょ！これ！
They stretch so much! Isn't this amazing?!
凄くない、これ？どんだけやってもめっちゃ伸びるからね！
Isn't it incredible? No matter how much I stretch, they flex so well!
ということで、はい。小ネタでした〜。
So, yes! That was a little fun fact~
はい。じゃあちょっとね、新しい衣装にもなりましたし、新しいステージにもなったということで...
Alright, so since I got a new outfit and a new stage...
じゃあちょっと...ちょっと1枚でもね、お写真撮りますか？写真。
Shall we take a photo, even just one? A photo.
このせっかくだし、この桜のさ、めっちゃ咲いてるところあるから、ここでちょちょっと撮ろうよ、撮ろうよ。
Since we're here, there's a spot with blooming cherry blossoms, so let's take some photos right here.
カメラさん来てください。こっちこっちこっち！
Cameraman, please come over! Over here, here, here!
あ、めっちゃ、めっちゃ映える！見て！すごいでしょ、これ！
Ah, it looks so photogenic! Look! Isn't this amazing!
めっちゃ綺麗だよね。このね、桜の色とかも、めっちゃ決めました。
It's super pretty. I was really particular about the color of these cherry blossoms.
あ、でもね、このライブ中にもめちゃめちゃ変わったりするので、ライティングとかもね...
Ah, but it changes a lot during the live performance, like the lighting...
変わったり、雰囲気もまた変わるので、それも含めて見てほしいんですけど...
and atmosphere shift, so I hope you look forward to all of that...
ま、ちょっとそれも含めて、ちょっとここでお写真なんか撮っちゃおうかな〜。
Taking all that into account, maybe I'll take a photo right here~
みんな、みんなスクショいっぱい撮ってくださいね。みんなハッシュタグ付けて、たくさんポストしてね！
Everyone, please take lots of screenshots, okay? Put the hashtag on and post them!
撮ってる？撮れてる？いい感じ？いい感じか？
Are you taking them? Got it? Looking good? Is it good?
じゃちょっと傘なしバージョンもちょっとやってみますか？
Then shall we try a version without the umbrella too?
どう？傘なし。傘なしもちょっと撮れるかしら。
How's this? Without the umbrella. Can you get a shot without it too?
お、いいんじゃない？いいんじゃない？あ、撮れてる？
Oh, isn't this good? Isn't this good? Ah, are you getting it?
お、撮れてますかね？お、めっちゃ、お、めっちゃいい角度じゃん！うわ、いいねいいねいいね！
Oh, are you capturing it? Wow, that's a super good angle! Nice, nice, nice!
へへ。はい！じゃあということで、お写真はね、これくらいにさせていただきまして...
Hehe. Alright! So with that, that'll be all for the photos...
えー、続きはね、ちょっと細かい衣装やら、ま、ちょっとスクショタイムは、ちょっと後々ね、用意しようかなと思うんで。
Um, as for the rest, like costume details and screenshot time, I'll set aside time for that later on.
ま、その後もね、ミニライブとかもありますので、そちらもぜひぜひチェックしていただければなと思います！
And after that, there will also be mini-lives, so please be sure to check those out as well!
そして！本日のハッシュタグはこちら！
And! Today's hashtag is this!
えー、ハッシュタグ「百鬼あやめ7周年新衣装3D」で！ちょっとね、長いんですけど...
Um, hashtag #百鬼あやめ7周年新衣装3D! It's a bit long, but...
長いんですけど、このたくさん綺麗にな、このステージとね、綺麗な衣装をたくさんたくさんスクショして、えー、一緒にポストしてください！
It's long, but please take lots of screenshots of this beautiful stage and outfit, and post them together!
はい！
Yes!
はい、ということで、今回はね、7周年を兼ねた...え、7周年！？ってことは、え、もう7年やってるんですか！？っていう感じなんですけど...
Alright, so this time, combining the 7th anniversary... wait, 7 years!? That means I've been doing this for 7 years already?!
えー、今回はその7周年とね、新衣装お披露目を兼ねたライブとなっております！
Um, this time it's a live stream combining the 7th anniversary and the new outfit reveal!
えー、これからね、ゲストもたくさん呼んでいますので、楽しみにしていてください！
Um, I've invited lots of guests coming up, so please look forward to it!
なんと！なんと！最後には、特大サプライズもあるので！えー、絶対に最後まで見逃さないでね！
And what's more! At the very end, there's a huge surprise! So don't miss it until the end!
チャンネルはそのままだよ！頼むね！
Stay tuned to this channel! Count on you!
夢の中でも 花が散ってる
Even in my dreams, flowers are falling,
ひらひら舞う 暗闇に浮かぶ桜
Fluttering and dancing, cherry blossoms floating in darkness.
水面に落ちたら
If they fall onto the water's surface...
君は もう一度咲くのかな
Will you bloom once more?
ひらひら ひらら
[Song Title: Hirahira Hirara]
桜月夜に宿る
Dwelling in the cherry blossom moonlit night,
いたずらな風 匂いだけ残して
A mischievous wind leaves only its scent behind...
騒ぎ出した
Awakened memories...
記憶は浮かび
surface,
沈んでいく
and sink away.
思い出の破片が
Even if fragments of memories
剥がれても
peel away,
光る鱗で隠すの
I hide them with glowing scales,
まばゆいほどに美しい
so dazzlingly beautiful.
ひらひら ひらら きらきら きらら
Fluttering, swaying, glittering, shining,
瞼の裏 暗闇に浮かぶ桜
cherry blossoms float in darkness behind my eyelids.
水面に落ちたら
If they fall onto the water's surface,
君はもう一度咲くのかな
will you bloom once more?
サヨナラしたら 会えないのでしょうか
If we say goodbye, will we never meet again?
言えないままの 気持ちだけが
Only these unsaid feelings
花びら浮かんだ 桜の橋になれ
become a bridge of cherry blossoms floating on water.
当たり前の景色が
The familiar scenery
ひらひらと舞い 音もなく消えてく
flutters and dances, disappearing without a sound.
細い雨に
Thoughts drenched
濡れた想いが 霞んでいく
by the fine rain grow faint.
他の誰かに向けた 笑顔を見て
Seeing the smile you directed at someone else,
忘れた日は蘇る
forgotten days come back to life,
色のない夜を 染めていく
coloring the colorless night.
君と出会った 去年の春と
The spring of last year when I met you,
同じ場所で 同じ景色見つめてた
watching the same scenery in the same place.
咲き誇るほどに痛む
Painful as it blooms in full pride,
君がいない桜
the cherry blossoms without you.
生まれ変わって また咲くのでしょうか
Reborn, will they bloom again?
戻れない場所と 知りながら
Knowing it's a place we cannot return to,
散り行く花びら 手のひらにのせて
placing the falling petals upon my palm.
花明かりに 誘われて
Enticed by the cherry blossom lights,
胸の中に 降り積もる
piling up inside my heart,
光と影 舞い散る吹雪の
light and shadow of the fluttering blizzard,
思い出だけ 白く染めていく
coloring only the memories white.
ひらひら ひらら きらきら きらら
Fluttering, swaying, glittering, shining,
瞼の裏 暗闇に浮かぶ桜
cherry blossoms float in darkness behind my eyelids.
水面に落ちたら
If they fall onto the water's surface,
君はもう一度咲くのかな
will you bloom once more?
サヨナラしたら 会えないのでしょうか
If we say goodbye, will we never meet again?
言えないままの 気持ちだけが
Only these unsaid feelings
花びらに変わっても
even if they turn into petals...
君と出会った 去年の春と
The spring of last year when I met you,
同じ場所で 同じ景色見つめてた
watching the same scenery in the same place.
咲き誇るほどに痛む
Painful as it blooms in full pride,
君がいない桜
the cherry blossoms without you.
夢の中でも 花が散ってゆく
Even in my dreams, flowers keep falling.
暗闇に浮かんだ 桜が
The cherry blossoms floating in darkness,
水面に落ちたら また会えるのかな
if they fall on the water, will we meet again?
極楽浄土
Gokuraku Jodo
月明かり昇る刻
Just as the moonlight rises
灯る赤提灯
Red lanterns light up the scene
祭囃子の合図
The festival music gives the signal
ふわり 蝶が 誘い出す
A butterfly softly entices you
ちょいと覗いて見てごらん
Why don't you take a quick peek?
迷い込めば 抜け出せない
Once you wander in, you can't escape
楽しいことがしたいなら
If you want to have some fun...
おいでませ 極楽浄土
Welcome to Paradise!
歌えや歌え 心のままに
Sing and sing to your heart's content
アナタの声を聞かせて
Now, let me hear your voice
踊れや踊れ 時を忘れ
Dance and dance, forgetting about time
今宵 共に あ狂い咲き
Tonight, let's bloom wildly together
美しく咲く花も
Even the flowers that bloom so beautifully
いつか散りゆくもの
Will eventually scatter and fade
それならこの一夜を
If so, then on this single night
もっと 熱く 愛したい
I want to love with even more passion
ちょいと「いいこと」いたしましょう
Shall we do something sweet?
これは夢か 幻か
Is this a dream or an illusion?
嘘も真も 無い世界
A world with neither lies nor truth
ゆきましょう 極楽浄土
Let's go to Paradise!
歌えや歌え 心のままに
Sing and sing to your heart's content
乱れる髪 息も気にせず
Careless of wild hair or catching breath
踊れや踊れ 時を忘れ
Dance and dance, forgetting about time
今宵 共に あ狂い咲き
Tonight, let's bloom wildly together
ちょいと「いいこと」いたしましょう
Shall we do something sweet?
嘘も真も 無い世界
A world with neither lies nor truth
ゆきましょう 極楽浄土
Let's go to Paradise!
歌えや歌え 心のままに
Sing and sing to your heart's content
アナタの声を聞かせて
Now, let me hear your voice
踊れや踊れ 時を忘れ
Dance and dance, forgetting about time
今宵 共に あ狂い咲き
Tonight, let's bloom wildly together
今宵 アナタと 狂い咲き
Tonight, blooming wildly with you
許婚っきゅん
[Song Title: Iinazukkyun]
どいつもしこいつ摩なんだかやっぱノーテンキ
Everyone seems so carefree after all
気になるあの子の悩みもきっとあるでしょ？
That girl I like must have her own troubles, right?
雑多でハンパな憂鬱どもは群れをなし
Random, half-baked worries gather in crowds
アタマの中はぐちゃぐちゃさ
My head is all cluttered up
ドンマイ弊害 意気地がないの 方程式
Don't mind the obstacles, equation of being a coward
イケナイイケナイ事柄なんてないから
Because there's no such thing as "forbidden"
イーアルサンスー じゃんけんぽんで さあお行き
Yi-Ar-San-Su! Rock-paper-scissors, off you go!
ウー リュー チー パークーで天に召されてく
Wu-Liu-Qi-Ba-Jiu, taken up to heaven!
キミはもうハイスピードだな
You're already going high speed
ありゃま こりゃま お待ちかね
Oh my, oh dear, just as expected!
ハチャでメチャなドラマ 派手にドラが乗るよ
A crazy, chaotic drama, hit the gong loud and clear!
い・い・許婚っきゅん I LOVE YOU なのだ
F-F-Fiancée-kyun, I LOVE YOU!
四六時中 愛を頂戴
Give me love 24/7!
はて？
Huh?
い・い・一か八っきゅん
A-A-All or Nothing-kyun!
い・哀・逢・愛♡罠ろっきゅー
L-O-V-E ♡ Trap rock you!
1/2じゃものたんない
Half-measures just aren't enough!
透けても結局見えないあいつの胸の内
Even if I can see through it, I can't read his inner heart
お邪魔虫 背伸びも気取りも要らないのかな
An intruder—is stretching or pretending unnecessary?
先輩 後輩 ヤンキー ジャンキー 関係ない
Senior, junior, delinquent, junkie, none of it matters
いざ尋常勝負
Now then, a fair fight!
君もしもその気なら
If you're in the mood for it
boy meets girl 始まりそうならさ
Boy meets girl, if it seems like it's starting
また犬の技繰り出す
Pulling off dog tricks again
僕らってば so sweet だな
We are so sweet, aren't we?
アレなところが同じだね
That weird side of us is just the same
へっちゃらぶで修羅場 派手にドラが鳴るよ
Unbothered love in a scene of chaos, the gong rings out loud
意味深な like you
A meaningful "like you"
曖昧な愛より直球
A straight pitch over vague love
しの言わず察して頂戴
Don't make excuses, just figure it out please
いちびるな天誅!
Don't get cocky, divine punishment!
鼻血ブーなのだ
Nosebleed spurting out!
自分の意志はどんなもんじゃい
How strong is your own will?
許婚っきゅん I love you なのだ
Betrothed-kyun, I love you!
四六時中愛を頂戴
Give me love 24/7
許婚っきゅん 愛愛愛愛わなっきゅん
Betrothed-kyun, love love love love wanna-kyun
1/2がもうたまんない
1/2 is already irresistible
これだって運命かもしれない
Even this might be fate
タイマン競っ先輩足りないや
Competing head-to-head, senior, it's not enough
千客万来 天真爛漫
Countless visitors, innocent and free-spirited
恋愛無条 明鏡止水で
Love's absurdity, with a clear mind and still water
せーの
Ready, set...
いーち にっ さん はい!
One, two, three, go!
いよーっ ぽん!
Iyooo... pon!
ハッハッハッハッハッハッハイヤ
Ha ha ha ha ha ha ha iya!
さささ これよりご覧いただきますのは歌舞伎者たちの
Now then, what you are about to witness are the kabukimono's...
栄枯盛衰 時代は常に日進月歩
...ups and downs; eras are always constantly advancing...
生きてってる老若男女
...living on, men and women of all ages.
一見は勧善懲悪 悪者はのちの一刀両断
At first glance rewarding good and punishing evil, bad guys cut down in a single stroke later—
「でもホントにそれだけで楽しいの?」
"But is that really all that's fun?"
もうなんだって問答無用
Whatever, no more questions asked!
ハッハッハッハッハッハッハイヤ
Ha ha ha ha ha ha ha iya!
いよーっ ぽん!
Iyooo... pon!
どこからともなく現れて直ぐどこかへ消えちゃう神出鬼没
Appearing out of nowhere and vanishing somewhere instantly, elusive...
チャンスを待ったら一進一退 追いかければ東奔西走
...waiting for a chance is back-and-forth, chasing after leads all over...
時代は常に千変万化 人の心は複雑怪奇
...eras are ever-changing, human hearts complex and strange.
「でも本気でそんなこと言ってるの?」
"But are you seriously saying that?"
もうどうにも満身創痍
Already completely covered in wounds!
嗚呼 巡り巡って夜の町
Ah, turning round and round in the night town...
キミは合図出し踊り出す
...you give the signal and start dancing.
はぁ〜
Haa~
回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ！
Spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin!
華麗に花弁散らすように
Like splendidly scattering flower petals...
回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ！
Spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin!
髪も振り乱して
...with your hair disheveled!
一昨日、昨日、今日と、明日と、明後日と この宴は続く
Day before yesterday, yesterday, today, tomorrow, day after tomorrow, this banquet continues...
踊レ、歌エ、一心不乱に回レ！
Dance, sing, spin with single-minded devotion!
今宵は雪月花
Tonight is Setsugetsuka!
いよーっ ぽん!
Iyooo... pon!
ハッハッハッハッハッハッハイヤ
Ha ha ha ha ha ha ha iya!
ねぇねぇねぇ この世に平安訪れるの? 鵺の鳴く夜丁々発止
Hey, hey, hey, will peace come to this world? On nights when the nue cries, fierce clashes occur...
千客万来 魑魅魍魎 群雄割拠
...countless visitors, evil spirits, rival warlords vying for power.
乗っ取られた一刻千金 気がついたら絶体絶命
Stolen precious moment, before you know it, total desperation!
「でも本気でそんなこと言ってんの?」
"But are you seriously saying that?"
もうまったく奇想天外
Completely outrageous!
嗚呼 辿り辿って夜の町
Ah, following and following through the night town...
迷い一つなく踊り出す
...dancing without a single hesitation.
はぁ〜
Haa~
回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ！
Spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin!
華麗に花弁散らすように
Like splendidly scattering flower petals...
回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ！
Spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin!
髪も振り乱して
...with your hair disheveled!
一昨日、昨日、今日と、明日と、明後日と この宴は続く
Day before yesterday, yesterday, today, tomorrow, day after tomorrow, this banquet continues...
踊レ、歌エ、一心不乱に回レ！
Dance, sing, spin with single-minded devotion!
今宵は雪月花
Tonight is Setsugetsuka!
ハッハッハッハッハッハッハイヤ
Ha ha ha ha ha ha ha iya!
ハッハッハッハッハッハッ
Ha ha ha ha ha ha!
花で一つ、鳥で二つ 手打ち鳴らす
One for flowers, two for birds, clapping hands.
風で三つ、嗚呼、月出て四つ 鳴らす鳴らす
Three for wind, ah, four for the moon coming out, clapping, clapping...
花で一つ、鳥で二つ 手打ち鳴らす
One for flowers, two for birds, clapping hands.
風で三つ、嗚呼、月出て四つ 鳴らす鳴らす
Three for wind, ah, four for the moon coming out, clapping, clapping...
今は
Right now,
回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ！
Spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin!
華麗に花弁 散らすように
Like scattering petals brilliantly,
回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ！
Spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin!
髪も振り乱して
Disheveling your hair as well!
一昨日、昨日、今日と、明日と、明後日と
The day before yesterday, yesterday, today, tomorrow, the day after,
この宴は続く
this banquet continues!
踊レ、歌エ、一心不乱に回レ！
Dance, sing, spin with all your heart!
今宵は何曜日か？
What day of the week is it tonight?
水木金？
Wednesday, Thursday, Friday?
土日月火？
Saturday, Sunday, Monday, Tuesday?
ハッハッハッハッハッハッハイヤ
Ha ha ha ha ha ha ha iya!
ハッハッハッハッ いよ〜〜っ ぽん！
Ha ha ha ha, iyo... pon!
宵々古今
[Song: Yoi Yoi Kokon]
らっしゃいな 平和は成り 時が来た 正しき 夢現 夜もすがら
Welcome, peace has arrived! The time has come, a true vision of dreams through the night.
変わりゆくことに 忘れじののっぴきならぬのはごめん
Amidst all the changes, forgive me for refusing to forget what cannot be avoided.
手毬唄歌い 君達が誘う
Singing a handball song, you all beckon me.
徒に後ろ髪を引かれても進むべきなり
Even if pulled back by regret, I must keep moving forward.
流行り廃りの浮き世なら
If this fleeting world is full of fading trends,
信ずる者はただ君だけと
then the only one I believe in is you.
踊り騒ぎや 飲みや歌いや 案ずることなどないな この世
Dance and make noise, drink and sing, there's nothing to worry about in this world!
人の世は恨めしい 節操はちゃらちゃら
The human world is bitter, integrity is fickle and frivolous.
騙し騙されて 満身創痍で それそれそれそれ
Deceiving and being deceived, covered in wounds—sore, sore, sore, sore!
今を咲いて 昔を憂いて
Blooming in the present, grieving the past,
己の心の内
within my own heart...
滾る涙川
a boiling river of tears.
それじゃ叶わん 過去に蹴回
That won't do! Kick away the past,
目眩く日々に 君を連れて
and take you with me into these dazzling days!
あまりてなどか いと悲しき 身勝手なのが世の理か
Why is it so painfully sad? Is selfishness simply the way of the world?
万人持つ理想 刻まんど 拙き答えなどはあらざらん
Etching the ideals held by all, there is no such thing as a clumsy answer.
巡り巡りあうこと まさに一期一会
Meeting again and again across time is truly a once-in-a-lifetime encounter.
試練 試練 甘いも辛いも 連れ添ってこの手握って
Trials and tribulations, sweet and bitter—stay by my side and hold this hand.
生きづらいこと 浮き世から 旗を掲げよ
From this hard-to-live floating world, raise high the flag!
宵闇が明く
The twilight brightens...
踊り上がり 照れは忘れる 昔も今も変わらず浮き世
Dance up, forget your shyness! Past or present, the floating world never changes.
人の世は悲しい いつだってちゃらちゃら
The human world is sad, always fickle and lighthearted.
可笑しさで笑って 意気消沈で それそれそれそれ
Laughing at the absurdity, downhearted—sore, sore, sore, sore!
深まる秋も 凍てつく雪の日も
In deepening autumn or freezing snowy days,
日出ずるすべての 輝きを君と見よう
let's watch every rising sun's brilliance together with you.
彩られ 前途なる見晴らしを 眺めて
Gaze upon the colorful, promising view lying ahead...
負けて勝つ一丸 欲しがる 欲しがる 欲しがる声
Losing to win as one! Demanding, demanding, greedy voices...
勝って選んで 呆気ないって泣いて
Winning and choosing, crying that it's too anti-climactic.
去るまで 幾喜以の 満足満ち足りないない
Until leaving, no amount of joy brings complete satisfaction!
未だ進む道半ば
Still halfway along the path we travel,
如何なる時も歩を前へ出せ
no matter when, take a step forward!
流行り廃りの 浮き世なら
If this fleeting world is full of fading trends,
信ずる者は ただ君だけと
then the only one I believe in is you...
踊り騒ぎや 飲みや歌いや 案ずることなどないな この世
Dance and make noise, drink and sing, there's nothing to worry about in this world!
人の世は恨めしい 節操はちゃらちゃら
The human world is bitter, integrity is fickle and frivolous.
騙し騙されて 満身創痍で それそれそれそれ
Deceiving and being deceived, covered in wounds—sore, sore, sore, sore!
今を咲いて 昔を憂いて
Blooming in the present, grieving the past,
己の心の内
within my own heart...
滾る涙川
a boiling river of tears.
それじゃ叶わん 何処に行っても
That won't do, no matter where I go!
めくるめく 舞台に 宵々 君を連れて
Taking you along to the dazzling stage, night after night...
あまりてなどか 人ぞ悲しき
Why must human beings be so filled with sorrow?
身勝手なのが 世の理か
Is selfishness simply the logic of this world?
うつろうは古今 香炉なら堂々
Things change throughout time; if like an incense burner, stand proud.
おそるることなどは あらざらむ
There shall be nothing to fear.
よ〜〜っ！
Yo~~~!
じゅげむ じゅげむ 五劫の擦り切れ
Jugemu, Jugemu, rubbing off of five kojos,
海砂利水魚の 水行末 雲来末 風来末
gravel of the sea, water fish, end of water's flow, clouds' origin, wind's destination,
食う寝るところに 住むところ
places to eat and sleep, places to live,
やぶらこうじの ぶらこうじ
bushes of spearflower,
ぱいぽ ぱいぽ ぱいぽの しゅーりんがん
Paipo, Paipo, Paipo's Shuringan,
しゅーりんがんの ぐーりんだい
Shuringan's Gurindai,
ぐーりんだいの ぽんぽこぴーの ぽんぽこなーの
Gurindai's Ponpokopi and Ponpokona,
長久命の 長助
Chokumei's Chosuke!
ちょいとお時間いただきます
May I take a bit of your time?
ご清聴ください 整いました！
Please lend me your ears! All set!
笑うことと かけまして
What do "laughter"...
お祭り野郎と ときます
...and "festival party animals" have in common?
そのこころは？ そのこころは？
What's the punchline? What's the punchline?
どちらも ハッピ（法被）になるでしょう
Both make you happy (wearing festival coats)!
おあとがよろしいようで
Thank you very much!
笑おう 笑おう さあ笑いましょう
Let's laugh, let's laugh, come on, let's laugh!
こんな時代こそ 笑いましょう
Especially in times like these, let's laugh!
笑おう 泣いたら負けだ
Let's laugh! If you cry, you lose!
やけくそ笑いましょう
Let me laugh out of pure desperation!
波乱万丈 酸いも甘いも
Through life's ups and downs, sweet and sour,
乗り越えた あっぱれ日本人
splendid Japanese who overcame it all!
笑おう
Let's laugh!
どんな時でも なにくそ笑いましょう
No matter when, let's laugh through grit and determination!
ぐわっはっは にょほほほ
Gwahaha, Nyohoho!
空気なんて読まずに笑っとけ
Without reading the room, just keep laughing!
笑顔！ 笑顔！
Smile! Smile!
笑う門には福来る！
Fortune comes to those who smile!
え〜皆様。今日はようこそおいでいただきました
Um~ Everyone, welcome and thank you for coming today!
ここで一席！！
Here's a story!
ねずみの娘がお嫁に行って、じきに返ってきたんで
A mouse's daughter got married and came right back,
ねずみのおかあさんが大変怒って、
so the mother mouse got furious and said,
「あんな、いいところへ、おまえ嫁いで、誰が嫌で出てきたんだい？」
"You married into such a nice family, who did you dislike so much that you left?"
「いいえ、だーれも嫌じゃないんですけれど、ご隠居さんがやさしいんで、嫌なの。」
"No, I didn't dislike anyone... but the retired father-in-law was gentle, so I hated it."
「やさしいんなら結構じゃないかねぇ。」
"If he's gentle, isn't that wonderful?"
「でも、猫なで声ですもの。」
"But he spoke in a coaxing voice!"
忙しさに身を任せて
Surrendering myself to busyness,
消えて行くだなんて べらんめぇ！
saying I'll fade away—don't be ridiculous!
笑おう 笑おう 笑えなくても
Let's laugh, let's laugh, even if you can't laugh,
笑うしか無いでしょ 笑いましょう
there's nothing to do but laugh, so let's laugh!
笑おう
Let's laugh!
口角上げて ひたすら笑いましょう
Turn up the corners of your mouth and just keep laughing!
応仁の乱 大飢饉さえ
Even through the Onin War and great famines,
クリアして現代 日本人
Japanese cleared them all to reach the modern era!
笑おう
Let's laugh!
未来永劫 グハハと笑いましょう
For all eternity, let me laugh out loud!
小娘のたわごとと 切り捨てないで
Don't brush it off as a young girl's nonsense!
しかめっつらなんか変な顔
Frowning makes such a strange face!
笑顔を見たいから
Because I want to see your smiling face!
笑おう 笑おう さあ笑いましょう
Let's laugh, let's laugh, come on, let's laugh!
こんな時代こそ 笑いましょう
Especially in times like these, let's laugh!
笑おう 泣いたら負けだ
Let's laugh! If you cry, you lose!
やけくそ笑いましょう
Let's laugh out of pure desperation!
波乱万丈 酸いも甘いも
Through life's ups and downs, sweet and sour,
乗り越えた あっぱれ日本人
splendid Japanese who overcame it all!
笑おう
Let's laugh!
どんな時でも なにくそ笑いましょう
No matter when, let's laugh through grit and determination!
ひたすら笑いましょう
Let's just keep laughing!
ぐわっはっは にょほほほ
Gwahaha, Nyohoho!
空気なんて読まずに笑っとけ
Without reading the room, just keep laughing!
笑顔！ 笑顔！
Smile! Smile!
笑う門には福来たる！
Fortune comes to a house with laughter!
死んでも夢を叶えたい！
Even if I die, I want to fulfill my dream!
いいえ 死んでも夢は叶えられる！
No, even if you die, your dream can come true!
それは絶望？それとも希望？
Is that despair? Or is it hope?
過酷な運命 乗り越えて
Overcoming a cruel fate,
脈がなくても突き進む
push forward even without a pulse!
それが私たちの SAGAだから
Because that is our SAGA!
誰が弔う 死地は彼方
Who mourns? The place of death lies far beyond...
静寂を破り 芽吹いた夢を
Breaking the silence, the dream that sprouted...
誓え 穿て
Swear it, pierce through!
重なる屍 高みへ
Atop the piling corpses, to the heights...
届くまで
...until it reaches!
唸れ 徒花 朽ち果てても進め
Roar, blighted flower! Keep advancing even if you rot away!
奪わせはしない 尊厳の愚弄に
We won't let them steal it! Against the mockery of our dignity...
飢餓を解き放て
...unleash the hunger!
枯れても走る ことを命と呼べ
Call running even when withered "life"!
空に叫ぶ 脱・生存の定義
Scream to the sky, defying the definition of survival!
骨を斬らせて 闇を断て
Let your bones be cut, sever the darkness!
雲間に光る 奪奪の勝機
The chance for victory shines between the clouds!
覚悟を 宿命に突きつけて
Thrust your resolve into destiny!
天下に狂い咲く
Bloom wildly across the world!
サガ SAGA
SAGA! SAGA!
傷ひとつ無い 手など愚か
Hands without a single scratch are foolish...
意思も自由も その身を投げて
Throw your body into will and freedom!
守れ 退くな
Protect it! Do not retreat!
涙も 血も無い 神話を
A myth with neither tears nor blood...
築くまで
...until it is built!
燃えろ 修羅花 鼓動亡き世界で
Burn, Asura flower! In a world without a heartbeat!
摂理に抗い 天命に無礼に
Defying providence, disrespecting destiny...
腐鎖切り抜けて
...break through the decaying chains!
心を無くす ことが死と知れ
Know that losing your heart is true death!
極めど儚い 偶像の寵児
The fleeting darling of idols at their peak!
目には目を剥き 牙を剥け
Turn an eye for an eye, bare your fangs!
いつか誰もが 散華する捨て石
Someday everyone becomes a stepping stone that falls in glory!
輝け 刹那無限の火花
Shine, sparks of an infinite moment!
乱世に奔る サガ SAGA
Racing through turbulent times, SAGA! SAGA!
何が神の冒涜か
What is blasphemy against God?
裁きなどさせない
We won't let anyone judge us!
希望 高らかに打ち鳴らせ
Ring out hope loud and clear!
呼吸よりも生きた証
Proof of having lived, more than mere breathing!
唸れ 徒花 朽ち果てても進め
Roar, blighted flower! Keep advancing even if you rot away!
奪わせはしない 尊厳の愚弄に
We won't let them steal it! Against the mockery of our dignity...
飢餓を解き放て
...unleash the hunger!
枯れても走る ことを命と呼べ
Call running even when withered "life"!
空に叫ぶ 脱・生存の定義
Scream to the sky, defying the definition of survival!
骨を斬らせて 闇を断て
Let your bones be cut, sever the darkness!
雲間に光る 奪奪の勝機
The chance for victory shines between the clouds!
覚悟を 宿命に突きつけて
Thrust your resolve into destiny!
荒野を駆ける 乱世に挑む
Dash through the wilderness, challenge these turbulent times!
天下に狂い咲く
Bloom wildly across the world!
サガ SAGA
SAGA! SAGA!
寄り添う二人に 君がオーバーラップ
You overlap with the cuddling couple
色なき風に 思い馳せて
I think of you in the colorless wind
触れた手の 温もり今も…
Even now, the warmth of your hand...
Stop 時間を止めて
Stop, stop the time
そう いつ分の日だって
Yes, no matter what day it is
君の言葉 忘れないの
I won't forget your words
会いたい時に会えない 会いたい時に会えない
When I want to see you, I can't; when I want to see you, I can't
切なくて もどかしい
It's painful and frustrating
から紅に染まる渡月橋
Togetsukyo Bridge dyed in crimson
導かれる日 願って
Praying for the day I'll be guided to you
川の流れに 祈りを込めて
Putting my prayers into the river's flow
I've been thinking about you
いつも 心 君のそば
My heart is always by your side
いにしえの景色 変わりなく
The ancient scenery remains unchanged
今この瞳に 映し出す
Reflected in these eyes right now
彩りゆく 季節越えて
Passing through the colorful seasons
Stock 覚えていますか？
Stock, do you remember?
ねぇ いつになったら
Hey, when will the time come
また巡り会えるのかな
That we can meet again?
会いたい時に会えない 会いたい時に会えない
When I want to see you, I can't; when I want to see you, I can't
この胸を焦がすの
Scorching this heart of mine
から紅に水くくる秋 君との想い繋げて
Autumn, when the water turns crimson, connecting my thoughts of you
川の流れに 祈りを込めて
Putting my prayers into the river's flow
I've been thinking about you
いつも 君を探してる
I'm always searching for you
君となら 不安さえ どんな時も消えていくよ
When I'm with you, even anxiety vanishes at all times
いつになったら 優しく 抱きしめられるのかな
When will I be able to be held tenderly in your arms?
から紅の紅葉達さえ 熱い思いを告げては
Even the crimson autumn leaves convey their burning feelings
ゆらり 揺れて 歌っています
Swaying gently, singing away
I've been thinking about you
いつも いつも 君想ふ
Always, always thinking of you
はい！というわけで、ここまでどうでしたでしょうかー？
Alright! So, how was it up until now?
いやー、もう数多くのゲストに出ていただいて、もう余は本当に嬉しいですー！本当に！
Wow, having so many guests appear, I'm really, really happy! Truly!
今回のね、ライブは最初にも言ったんですけど、ちょっと和風な感じでまとめてさせていただいたので
As I said at the beginning of this live stream, I put everything together with a Japanese theme,
曲ももうほぼほぼ全部和風っぽい感じで、ちょっと雰囲気をね、ひとつに統一して、今回はライブを作らせていただきましたー！
so almost all the songs were Japanese-style too! I unified the atmosphere into one to create this live stream!
そして、みんな気づいたかな？ちょっと歌ってる最中、ちょっと気づきました？これ。
And, did everyone notice? While I was singing, did you notice this?
おっ、気づきましたー！新しいマイクなんですよー！
Oh, you noticed! It's a new microphone!
いや、すごいでしょー！すごいでしょー！え、みてみて、このちょっと…この、分かりますか？このお腹の柄と…
Isn't it amazing? Isn't it great? Hey, look at this... can you tell? This pattern on the stomach and...
ちょっと おそろいなんですよ
They're matching!
ちょっと こっちも… あ、見えるかな？
On this side, too... Ah, can you see it?
見える？
Can you see?
ほら！え、めっちゃ可愛いでしょ、これ！
Look! Isn't this super cute?
イエーイ！これ、新しいマイク。
Yay! This is my new microphone.
あ、ここもね、飾りも付いてるんですよ、この鈴と
Ah, there are decorations attached here too, like this bell...
この紐もね、付いてて、可愛いでしょ～
...and this cord is attached as well. Cute, right?
はい！
Yeah!
これもね、おNEWです！
This is new too!
ヤッター！
Yay!
はい、ということで！
Alright, with that said...
えー、今回はですね、まだサプライズが残っております！
Well, this time, we still have a surprise left!
ですが！
However!
えー、その前にちょっと告知をさせていただこうかなと思います！
Before that, I'd like to make a quick announcement!
それでは、告知ドドン！
Now then, here's the announcement! Badam!
百鬼あやめ活動7周年記念グッズ～！イエーイ！
Nakiri Ayame 7th Anniversary Commemorative Goods~! Yay!
はい！えー、ということで、最初は、こちら！
Alright! First up, we have this!
卓上屏風です！
It's a tabletop folding screen!
めっちゃ可愛いでしょ！すごい！
Isn't it super cute? Amazing!
でしょ～？えーっと、デスクに立てて飾れるサイズの屏風となっております。
Right? It's a folding screen sized to stand and display on your desk.
こちらはですね、我美蘭先生の描き下ろしの余の... 本日着ている新衣装と同じです！
This features a new illustration by Gabiran-sensei, showing me in the exact same new outfit I'm wearing today!
同じ屏風をね、ちょっと飾ってくださいね、みんな。
Everyone, please display this matching screen, okay?
あ、可愛いでしょ！このね、ステージも
Ah, cute, right? The stage in the background...
背景のステージも、ちょっとそれっぽい感じに合わせてもらいました。
...was designed to match the atmosphere of this stage too!
可愛い～！
So cute!
続いて～！こちら！
Next up! This one!
湯呑となっております！
It's a teacup!
え、こちらはですね、三川あゆむ先生に描き下ろしいただいた
This features a new illustration by Mikawa Ayumu-sensei...
え、ぽよよに乗ったですね、今回もこちらの新衣装でに乗った余がミニキャラで描かれた湯呑となっております！
...with a chibi version of me sitting on Poyoyo in this new outfit, printed on the teacup!
可愛いでしょう！こうやって、乗ってます！乗ってます！
Isn't it cute? See, I'm riding on it! Riding on it!
はい！可愛いでしょ！
Yep! Cute, right?
そして！続いてはこちら！
And next is this!
こちら扇子となっております！
This is a folding fan!
こちらはですね、気づきますか？
Do you notice this?
こちらもそうです！新衣装と同じ柄の扇子となっております。
That's right! This fan features the same pattern as my new outfit.
ちょっとね、ど真ん中に「余」って入ってるんですけど、こちら...
The character "Yo" is right in the center, and...
え、入れるかすごい迷いました。これ「余」を入れる... 入れようかな？え、どうしようかな？とお兄さんとちょっと話し合って、こちらになりました！
I really debated whether to include "Yo". I discussed with staff if I should put it, and this is what we decided on!
ちょっとね、あのー、この「余」の右左でこう... 余のこれかな？
To the left and right of "Yo", it matches the colors...
この振袖と同じ、こっちの色とこっちの色で、ちょっとね新衣装っぽい感じにさせていただきました！
...of these sleeves, giving it a feel that matches the new outfit!
そして！続いて、こちら！
And next, this one!
卓上ライトとなっております！
This is a tabletop light!
行灯風の卓上ライトで、新衣装にこちらもですね、合わせた和風のデザインとなっております。
It's a Japanese lantern style tabletop light, designed in a traditional style to match the new outfit.
ぜひね、飾って、あの和風っぽい風情あるお部屋タイムをね、過ごしていただきたいなということで
I hope you'll display it to create an atmospheric, Japanese-style mood in your room...
ちょっと和風よりのライトにさせていただきました！
...so we made it a traditional Japanese-style light!
可愛いでしょう、これ！いいよね！めっちゃ考案しました、こちら。おすすめです！はい！
Isn't it cute? So nice, right? I put a lot of thought into this one. Highly recommended! Yep!
はい、続いてこちら！
Alright, next is this!
こちらはですね、おなじみ販売ボイス！こちらのタイトルは「新衣装でデート」
This is the familiar voice pack! The title is "A Date in the New Outfit".
ということで、内容は新衣装の余と水辺で...
The content is a date with me in my new outfit by the water...
え？水辺？でデートをする内容となっております！
Wait, by the water? A date scene set near the water!
ステージにもね、ちょっと水辺、後ろにありますけども。はい！
On stage too, there's water behind me. Yep!
はい！そしてそして！フルセットを購入の方は、こちらです！
And for those who purchase the full set, here it is!
数量限定バージョンは、直筆サイン＆箔押し複製メッセージ入り、我美蘭先生描き下ろしのポストカードとなっております！
The limited edition set includes a postcard illustrated by Gabiran-sensei, featuring a handwritten signature and foil-stamped message!
可愛い～！
So cute~!
通常バージョンはですね、箔押し複製サインとメッセージ入りの我美蘭先生描き下ろしポストカードとなっております！
The regular version includes the postcard illustrated by Gabiran-sensei with a foil-stamped copy signature and message!
さらに！新衣装をリスナーに褒めてもらって喜んでいる余の特典ボイスが付いてきますね！
Plus, it comes with a bonus voice track where I get happy when listeners praise my new outfit!
タイトル「またデートしようね」という... これ一体何なんだという感じなんですけど
The title is "Let's Go on Another Date"... What even is that, right?
まあね、気になった方はぜひ聞いていただければと思います。恥ずかしいのでここら辺にしときまーす！
Well, if you're interested, please check it out! I'm embarrassed, so I'll stop here!
はい！ということで以上、百鬼あやめ活動7周年記念グッズでした！
Alright! That concludes the Nakiri Ayame 7th Anniversary Commemorative Goods!
みんな買ってね！よろしくお願いします！
Everyone, please buy them! Thank you so much!
...と言うことなんですけど！
...or so I say!
こちら！まだ終わってません！
Look! It's not over yet!
まだチャンネルはそのままで頼む！
Please stay on this channel!
ということで、まあね、最初ちょっと言った、そろそろまあサプライズをね
So, like I mentioned at the beginning, it's time for the surprise...
みんな気になってると思うんで、ちょっとサプライズに行っちゃおうかなと思います！
I think everyone is curious, so let's move on to the surprise!
みんな気になるよね！
Everyone's curious, right?
気になる気になる～！
I know you are!
え、そうですよね～！と！
That's right~! And...
その前に！
Before that!
このステージ、上へ参ります！
This stage is going UP!
ぐんぐんぐん… うわっ！上がってる！
Going up up up... Woah! It's ascending!
みんな見て、すごいでしょ！見えてる？見えてる～？
Everyone look, isn't it amazing? Can you see it?
みんな見て！ステージも余も見て！
Everyone look! Look at the stage and me!
はい！ということで...
Alright! So...
こちら上に上がってきたんですけれども
I've come up here to the upper stage,
ま、上でね何をやのるのかと
and you might wonder what I'm going to do up here...
ま、うすうすちょっと気づいてるんじゃないかなとは思うんですけれども
I think some of you might have an inkling,
何かわかるかな？みんな。
Do you know what it is, everyone?
教えて、教えて、教えて！みんな何だと思う？
Tell me, tell me, tell me! What do you think it is?
おー、ちらほら、あー、当たってますね。うんうん、なんと！
Oh, I see some... Oh, you got it right! Yes, yes!
はい、こちら、なんとこちらです！ドドン！
Yes, this! It's actually this! Ta-da!
新曲「花吹雪」です！やったー！
My new song, "Hanafubuki"! Yay!
いや、もうだいぶ長らくお待たせしたと思うんですけれども、
I know I've kept you waiting for a long time,
余のオリジナルの新しいのはいつだ？みたいな感じで待っていたかと思うんですけど、
and you were waiting like, "When is her next original song?"
こちら、作詞作曲Vellさんに書いていただきました！ありがとうございます！
Vell composed and wrote the lyrics for this song! Thank you!
テーマはですね、可憐な歌声×和風ロック。
The theme is "lovely singing voice x Japanese-style rock."
かわいいだけじゃない、一味違うオリジナルソングとなっております！
It's an original song that's not just cute, but has a unique edge!
はい、こうね、綺麗で可憐で重厚な和風ロックとなっておりますので、
Yes, it's a beautiful, lovely, and heavy Japanese-style rock song,
メロディーとかね、歌詞もこだわり抜いて磨き上げていただいた楽曲となっておりますので、
and with great care paid to the melody and lyrics, it was polished to perfection,
ぜひぜひ皆さん聴いてください！
so please, everyone, make sure to listen to it!
9月4日0時から、本日の0時からですね、各音楽配信サイトでリリースされるのでぜひ聴いてください！聴いてね、いっぱい聴いてね！
It will be released on streaming sites at midnight tonight, September 4th! Listen to it a lot!
はい、それでは皆さん、大変長らくお待たせいたしました！
Alright then, everyone, thank you so much for waiting so long!
最後はこの新曲「花吹雪」でお送りしたいと思います！
To finish off, I'd like to perform this new song, "Hanafubuki"!
感想などもね、この衣装もステージと一緒にポストしてください！たくさんポストしてね！
Please post your thoughts about the outfit and stage! Post a lot, okay?
最後にですね、メンゲンパートでちょっと衣装のお写真になったり、詳しい感じのお話もしたり、
Finally, in the member-exclusive part, I'll show photos of the outfit and chat in detail,
ミニライブもありますので、そちらの方もぜひぜひ見に来てくれたら嬉しいです！
and there's also a mini-live, so I'd be happy if you came to watch that too!
はい！それではお聴きください、「花吹雪」！
Alright! Please listen to "Hanafubuki"!
共に散る 宿命なら
Together we scatter, if that is our fate
派手に散りましょう
Let us scatter in grand fashion
花吹雪
A flurry of falling blossoms
ひらひら舞い落ちる空 共に散った 泡沫の夢
Fluttering down from the sky, a transient dream scattered together
千の花は 麗しく咲く 叶う逢瀬は刹那
A thousand flowers bloom beautifully, the granted meeting is but a fleeting moment
艶やかに舞う 蝶の儚き命
Dancing elegantly, the fragile life of a butterfly
するり 堕ちる 今宵は何処
Slipping down, where shall we fall tonight?
天の風 揺れる
The heavenly winds sway
狂おしく 今 咲き誇れ
Wildly, bloom in all your glory now
共に散る 宿命なら 光満ちた 舞台で華ね
If it's our fate to scatter together, bloom on a stage filled with light
闇を裂く 旋律は ゆらりと薫る
The melody piercing through darkness gently wafts its scent
夢を咲かせましょう 花吹雪
Let us make our dreams bloom, a flurry of falling blossoms
くらくら燃ゆるは焔 遠く咲いた 明日の夢
Dizzily burning are the flames, a dream of tomorrow blooming far away
正か否か 惑わずに進む 過去の痛みを胸に
Whether right or wrong, I forge ahead without hesitation, holding past pain in my chest
誰そ彼に 祈りをひとつ
In the twilight, a single prayer
涙の川を 穿つ声響く
Echoing, a voice pierces the river of tears
慎ましく ただ進むだけ
Modestly, I simply keep moving forward
茜さす 空の果てで 褪せた過去の 憧れを見る
At the edge of the madder-red sky, I look upon faded longings of the past
澄み渡る 静寂に 未来を繋ぐ
In the crystal-clear silence, connecting to the future
答え求めど にべも無し
Though I seek answers, there is no response
星の降る夜明けまで 続く歌よ 彼方へ届け
Until dawn when stars fall, may this continuing song reach far away
湧き上がる情熱が 世界を照らす
The surging passion illuminates the world
共に散る 宿命なら
If it is our fate to scatter together,
光満ちた 舞台で笑え
Smile upon a stage filled with light.
闇を裂く 旋律は
The melody that tears through the darkness...
ゆらりと薫る
...wafts gently and fragrantly.
夢を咲かせましょう
Let us make our dreams blossom,
花吹雪
In a flurry of cherry blossoms!